- [Man] Sorry, confirm left side.
Yeah, put me over.
- [Man] Is he sort of moving towards us?
- [Man] Negative, he's speeding.
If you come right, you'll
come over to open ground here,
you'll see him from this angle.
(helicopter blades whirring)
- Okay, cool.
Might find him this way.
- [Man] Could you circle them,
and we'll go higher.
- [Man] I can just see his
head through the bush there.
(lighthearted music)
- [Narrator] It was believed
that they were a bygone
group of elephants.
Many people didn't realize
that these elephants actually existed.
(engine revving)
The super tusker is an elephant
that has ivory that reaches the ground.
Those individuals, they are truly
ambassadors in the elephant world.
They have age, they have
respect from other elephants,
they've had to endure
immense, immense challenges
from drought, to poachings.
They've endured shrinking
elephant habitats,
and human greed,
so imagine what a story he could tell.
Tsavo is a big place.
It's vast,
and I believe it is Kenya's
last true wilderness area
that holds significant wildlife.
(elephant roaring)
(elephants trumpeting)
And then, of course,
there's the big tusker.
There's less than 25 left on the planet.
I mean, can you imagine having
known and experienced
with these elephants,
just the thought that
there would be no more?
By and large, it's just live
for today and not tomorrow,
is it's this perpetual
circle of living for now
and not the future.
I truly believe that more
people need to wake up
and understand that actually,
they're being pushed to the brink.
(engine revving)
- [Man] Yeah, that's your own boy in there
just on my left, that's the guy.
- [Man] Okay, alright, we'll do this.
Is (mumbling) there?
- [Man] I haven't seen him yet.
- [Narrator] I think there are ways
that coexistence between humans
and wildlife can work in certain aspects.
(speaking foreign language)
But many of the local people
in the communities that we support,
they're thinking about
where their next meal is gonna come from.
(gentle music)
But you can change that mindset
that an elephant is a bad thing.
It's a crop raider, it's
killed family members,
it's a hard thing to change
and it's a long process,
but I believe it's possible.
If you have space available,
there is a chance that wildlife
and humans can coexist.
Because if you've go the space
and you've got the habitat,
just give it time, give it commitment,
and everything else falls into place.
(speaking foreign language)
Searching for those
tuskers on a regular basis,
you're providing an extra
layer of security for them,
eyes in the skies, and eyes
and ears on the ground.
(whistling)
The hope is that with
that security and presence
they will pull through
the next five or 10 years.
In this mad world that we live in,
the fact that there are elephants in Tsavo
that are reaching their full lifespan
and they're dying of old age,
just that in itself is a huge positive.